
<chapter><title>What software does &ep2; need? Where do I get it?</title>
<para>This is a very rough and ready guide. This is alpha software, if you want spell checking wait for the beta...</para>
<para>Suggestions to improve these instructions are welcome.</para>
<sect1><title>Where to get the Required Software From</title>
<para>It's up to you, we have found that installing from source is more effective than RPM's, feel free to dispute this. The best place to get a software tool is the official site, but we've put a mirror of versions known to work at:
<ulink href="http://www.eprints.org/files/tools/">http://www.eprints.org/files/tools/</ulink></para> 
</sect1>
<sect1><title>Apache/mod_perl</title>
<para>
The Apache HTTP server was designed as a plug-in replacement for the NCSA server (version 1.4). It fixes numerous bugs in the NCSA server, and includes many new features - including an API to make user extension easier. EPrints requires Apache to be configured with mod_perl, as this allows Apache modules that are entirely written in perl, hence providing much improved efficiency.
</para>
<para>
Downloads
<itemizedlist mark="opencircle">
<listitem><ulink>http://httpd.apache.org/dist/httpd/</ulink></listitem>
</itemizedlist>
</para>
<para>Required modules: mod_perl and mod_rewrite</para>
<procedure><title>Apache with mod_perl Installation</title>
<step><para>
Download Modperl and apache sources
</para></step>
<step><para>
Make mod_perl, I use this command (in the modperl src dir):
<screen>
perl Makefile.PL APACHE_PREFIX=/usr/local/apache APACHE_SRC=../apache-1.3.14/src DO_HTTPD=1 USE_APACI=1  PERL_AUTHEN=1 PERL_AUTHZ=1 ADD_MODULE=rewrite</screen>
</para></step>
<step><para>
Make and install apache. From the apache src dir, I use:
<screen>
make
make install
</screen>
( mod perl should have already done the ./configure for us. )
</para></step>
</procedure>
</sect1>

<sect1><title>MySQL</title>
<para>Install a recent version of MySQL. You will need the .h and library files later to install the MySQL perl module. (more help in later version of docs).</para>

</sect1>

<sect1><title>Perl 5.6</title>
<para>&eprints; is currently begin developed with perl 5.6.1, there are currently no plans for a perl 6 version.</para>
<sect2><title>Installing a Perl Module</title>
<para>This describes the way to simple perl module, some require a bit more effort. We will use DBI as an example.</para>
<procedure><title>How to install a Perl Module</title>
<step><para>
Unpack the archive:
<screen>tar xzvf DBI-1.14.tar.gz</screen>
</para></step>
<step><para>
Enter the directory this creates:
<screen>
cd DBI-1.14
</screen>
</para></step>
<step><para>
Run the following commands:
<screen>
perl Makefile.PL
make
make test
make install
</screen>
</para></step>
</procedure>
</sect2>

<sect2><title>Required Perl Modules</title>

<formalpara>
<title>CGI</title>
Should be installed by default. Note that CGI 3.02 should not be used, as it contains a bug in its handling of multipart forms. Version 2.75 appears to be stable, and is the version that we are using for testing.
</formalpara>

<formalpara>
<title>Data::Dumper</title>
Should be installed by default. This module is used by the installer, and for debugging. It should be easy to install if not already present.
</formalpara>

<formalpara>
<title>DBI</title>
The generic database connection module. No known issues with installation.
</formalpara>

<formalpara>
<title>Msql-Mysql modules</title>
This one can be difficult. It requires access to .h and library files from MySQL. I install MySQL from source first, but some installs of MySQL don't put the lib and include dirs where this module expects. 
The answer to the first question is that you only need MySQL support.
</formalpara>

<formalpara>
<title>Filesys::DiskSpace</title>
This is an annoying little module as it requires some system headers to be created. If it gives you trouble try the following:
<para>Fixing Filesys::DiskSpace (Linux)
<screen>
cd /usr/include
h2ph * */*
</screen></para>
<para>Fixing Filesys::DiskSpace (Solaris)
<screen>
cd /usr/include
h2ph asm/* bits/*
</screen></para>
</formalpara>

<!-- Not used? maybe need it later for mail?
<formalpara>
<title>MIME-Base64</title>
</formalpara>
-->

<formalpara>
<title>Unicode::String</title>
Used for Unicode support. No known problems.
</formalpara>

<formalpara>
<title>URI</title>
Used for processing URL strings. No known problems.
</formalpara>

<formalpara>
<title>Apache::AuthDBI</title>
Allows apache to authenticate users from a database table, via modperl and DBI.
</formalpara>

<!-- ???
<formalpara>
<title>HTML::Parser</title>
</formalpara>
-->

<!--
<formalpara>
<title>LWP</title>
</formalpara>
-->

<formalpara>
<title>XML::Parser</title>
Used to parse XML files. Requires the <application>expat library</application> and the ExtUtils:PerlPP Perl module. A .tar.gz and a RedHat Linux RPM are available in the tools dir on eprints.org for the expat library, and the ExtUtils:PerlPP module is easy to install if not already present.
</formalpara>

<!-- What is this for??
<formalpara>
<title>libxml-enno</title>
</formalpara>
-->

</sect2>
</sect1>
<sect1><title>wget, unzip  and others</title>
<para>Later versions may require (or require for full functionality) other software, but this version does not do anything which requires them yet...</para>
</sect1>
</chapter>
